Conditional functions and spreadsheets are part of the logical functions group.
电子表格中的条件函数属于逻辑函数
We'll start with If.
我们将从 if 函数开始
The function If, like other functions,
和其他函数一样
starts out with an equal sign, then if,
if 函数以等号开头 然后是 IF
then some parameters which are a condition,
然后是作为条件的参数
what to do if the condition is true,
如果条件为真 该怎么操作
and optionally what to do if it's false.
以及可选情况下如果条件为假 该怎么办
These parameters can be constants or
这些参数可以是常量或单元格引用
cell references or other functions. Here's an example.
或其他函数 看个示例
A conditional sentence written in English might be something like,
用英语表述的条件语句可以是
if there were more apples than oranges in the order, print Apples Rule.
如果订单中苹果多于橘子 则输出“Apples Rule!”
The condition is that there are more apples than oranges,
条件是苹果比橘子多
and the value, if true,
值如果为真
is the statement, Apples Rule.
则输出语句 “Apples Rule!”
How would we do this in a fruit stand spreadsheet?
如何在水果摊电子表格中实现这一情况
It's a function, so start with equal, if,
它是一个函数 因此以等号开始 输入 if
open parentheses, the apples sell,
左括号 苹果所在单元格
now a comparison operator meaning greater than,
表示大于的比较运算符
then the oranges sell, comma,
橘子所在单元格 逗号
and what to print in double quotes: Apples Rule,
然后是用双引号包含在内的输出内容：Apples Rule!
close parentheses and fill down.
闭合括号 向下填充
Notice that it just says false,
注意 那些显示 FALSE
if apples don't rule because I didn't fill in what to do if the value is false.
因为我没有设定 if 条件为假时的填充值
I can fix that by changing my statement to include
我可以修改下 将输出语句改为
an output such as Oranges Rock for the false situation.
针对条件为假时 输出为“Oranges Rock”
So my new statement in English would be,
因此新的语句用文字表述就是
if there are more apples than oranges in the order,
如果订单中苹果比橘子多
print Apples Rule, else, print Oranges Rock.
则输出 Apples Rule! 否则输出 Oranges Rock
For this little example,
对于该示例
I use the greater than sign as a comparison operator.
我使用大于号作为比较运算符
Comparison operators are used in logic statements to compare two values.
比较运算符在逻辑语句中用来比较两个值
In addition to greater than,
除了大于 &gt;
there are operators for less than,
还有小于 &lt;
equal, greater than or equal,
等于 =、大于等于 &gt;=
less than or equal, and not equal.
小于等于 &lt;= 以及不等于 &lt;&gt; 运算符
They're shown here with an operator symbol in Excel.
它们在 Excel 中就是这些符号
Any of these comparison operators can be used to create a true or false condition,
任何一个比较运算符都可以用来创建真假条件
and that's what the if statement will evaluate following your instructions for each.
if 语句就是根据你的每个说明 对这些运算符进行评估
It's time for you to give this a try.
现在该你来试试了